-Thanks for the tasty dinner. -You're welcome for a tasty dinner.
謝謝你煮的好料 隨時都歡迎
What are you guys looking at?
你們在看什麼？
Ross and the most beautiful girl in the world.
羅斯和宇宙無敵第一美女
Yeah,come to Papa!
好騷的娘兒們
I know!
我知道
Probably the only time I'll say this...
這實在不像我會說的話
...but did you see the ass on her?
但你們看到她的屁股了嗎？
What did you...? When did you...?
你是…你是…
How did you...? How did you get a girl like that?
你怎麼… 你怎麼把到那種貨色的？
So what is she,like a spokesmodel? An aerobics instructor?
她是誰，代言模特兒？ 有氧舞蹈教練？
Actually,she's a paleontology doctoral candidate...
她是古生物學博士候選人
...specializing in the Cenozoic Era.
專攻新生代
But that's,like,the easiest era.
不過那是最簡單的時代
I've seen her at work, but I always figured....
我在館裡見過她，但總覺得…
But I made her dinner.
總之我做飯給她吃
We had a great time. And we're going out again tomorrow.
我們聊得很愉快 明天還要見面
Maybe her friends are betting to see who gets the biggest geek.
也許她跟朋友打賭 誰能釣到最怪的怪胎
Fine by me. Hope she wins.
我無所謂，祝她勝利
Hey,we should have a contest. Yeah.
我們也應該來比
See who can bring home the most beautiful woman.
看誰帶回來的女生最漂亮
That's a good idea,Joe. We could call it life.
好主意 名稱就叫「真實人生」
The One with the Dirty Girl
本集播出：「送禮風波」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
You have any wrapping paper?
有包裝紙嗎？
Is it for my birthday present?
你要包我的生日禮物？
It was your birthday months ago.
你生日都過了1個月
You said you ordered something special and it just hadn't come yet.
對，但你說訂了特別的東西 還沒送來
I have a call in about that.
我有接到電話
It's for Kathy. It's an early copy of her favorite book.
這是給凱西的生日禮物 是她最喜歡的書的早期版本
The Velveteen Rabbit!
是「天鵝絨兔寶寶」
When the boy's love makes the rabbit real....
天哪 當男孩的愛讓它變成真兔子…
Don't touch it because your fingers have destructive oils.
好，別摸，你的手有油污
Then you'd better keep it away from Ross' hair.
那你最好別靠近羅斯的頭髮
This is pretty rare. How did you get that?
這很珍貴，你是怎麼找到的？
No big deal. I just went to some bookstores...
沒什麼，我只是跑了幾家書店 問了幾個書商
...talked to some dealers,called some of the author's grandchildren.
聯絡了幾個作者的孫子
Honey,that's so sweet.
真是太感人了
What a great way to say,"l secretly love you,roommate's girlfriend."
完全宣告了 「室友的馬子，我在暗戀你」
It doesn't say that.
哪會啊…
Does it?
會嗎？
How will it look when you get her something incredibly meaningful...
你自己看嘛 你送的禮物別具意義又昂貴
...and expensive,and her boyfriend, Joey,gives her an orange?
她的男朋友卻送她一個柳橙
I'll make sure Joey gets her something really great.
好 我會叫喬伊送她很好的禮物
It's got to be better than that book.
可得比那本書還好
Like a crossbow!
像十字弓啦
Once again,I am sorry.
真的很抱歉
Thank you. Bye.
謝謝，再見
I had to turn down a job catering a funeral for 60 people.
我推掉一個60人的喪禮外燴
Oh,my God! What happened?
天哪，出了什麼事？
Sixty guests.
是60個「客人」
Why'd you have to turn it down?
你為什麼要推掉？
I don't have the money or equipment...
因為我沒有錢和用具
...to handle something that big on such short notice.
可以臨時接這種大生意
Wow,what is with all the negativity?
這麼消極是怎麼回事？
You sound like "Moni-can't," not "Moni-can"!
你好像「摩妮不可」 而不是「摩妮可」
Moni-ca.
摩妮「卡」
You've been playing around with this catering for years.
你辦外燴都3年多了
-Do you want to be a caterer? -I don't know.
你到底想不想當外燴廚師？ 我不知道
There you go! That's the spirit!
這就對了！
If you need money,I will lend you money. Just get moving!
你需要錢我借你，你就接吧
Really? I'd need $500 for all the food and supplies.
真的？我需要5百元來採買
It's worth it if it'll get you moving. You haven't worked in months!
好，能讓你接就值得 你好幾個月沒工作了
-Neither have you. -Yes,but I'm doing this.
你也是 但我正在資助你
That would be great! Thank you.
太好了，謝謝
-Can I borrow your apartment keys? -Why?
你家的鑰匙借我 為什麼？
You can pee here.
你可以在這裡尿啊
Yes,I can,of course.
也對
It's okay. The duck's using our bathroom anyway.
不好意思 反正剛好鴨子也在用浴室
What are you getting for her birthday?
你要送她什麼生日禮物？
We've been dating a couple weeks. I got to get her something?
我們才交往2星期也要送嗎？
You have to get her something really nice.
要啊 不但要送，還要送得很好
-I know! -And not one of your coupons...
有了！ 1小時的...
...for an hour of "Joey Love."
...喬伊猛男體驗券不算
-A crossword! Can I help? -No.
填字遊戲！我可以幫忙嗎？ 不行
Last week I got all but three answers...
對不起 可是上星期我幾乎全答對了
...and I want to finish one without any help.
我很想獨力完成一次
Fine.
好
But you can't help me develop my new universal language.
那你也不能幫我研發新宇宙語
How'd it go?
怎麼樣？
Oh,my God! It was the best funeral ever!
天哪，這個葬禮太棒了
Everyone loved the food.
每個人都說好吃
I even got another funeral for tomorrow.
我還接了明天的另一場葬禮
The dead guy from today's best friend.
是今天的死者的死黨
It's like I am the official caterer for that accident.
我成了那場事故的指定外燴
Mon,I'm so happy for you!
我真替你高興
Thanks. Check out my new catering stuff.
謝了，你看我的新用具
Look! I'm an omelet station!
看，我可以去賣蛋卷
Omelet? Made to order?
要特製蛋卷嗎？
I'll have one,please. Plus my money.
請給我一份，還有我的錢
I didn't realize you needed it right away.
我不曉得你馬上就要
You told me to go and be a caterer. So I went. I be'd.
你叫我去當外燴廚師 我就去了
I used it to buy all this stuff.
我把錢都花掉了
Aborigine.
「原住民」！
不對
I got another job tomorrow, so I'll pay you back then.
我明天還有生意 到時就能還你
Okay. Sorry I acted like a bank.
好，抱歉剛才一副銀行嘴臉
Aborigine. Oh,no,I tried that already.
「原住民」！ 不對，我已經試過了
Would you like to come in?
你要進來嗎？
Did Homo erectus hunt with wooden tools?
直立人是用木器打獵嗎？
According to recent findings.
最新證據顯示是的
Here,Mitzi! Here,Mitzi!
蜜琪來，蜜琪來
Mitzi is...?
蜜琪是…
My hamster.
我的倉鼠
I hope she's okay. I haven't seen her in a while.
但願它沒事，好久沒見到它了
Have a seat.
請坐
Where?
（坐哪裡？）
Oh,hey. Do you....
對了，你…
Do you have any Cinnamon Fruit Toasties?
你有肉桂水果烤吐司嗎？
Well,I do.
什麼？ 我有
Let's go back to my place, light a couple candles...
我們回我家去，點幾根蠟燭
...break open a box of Cinnamon Fruit Toasties....
開一盒肉桂水果烤吐司
-I'd rather not. -Oh,yeah? Why not?
還是不要好了 為什麼？
Don't take this the wrong way...
我沒有惡意
...but your place kind of has a weird smell.
但是你家有一股怪味
-ls everything in the car? -Did you settle the bill?
東西都上車了？ 對，錢拿到了嗎？
I hate this part.
還沒，我最討厭要錢了
Look what we almost left!
差點忘了這個
That's not mine.
那不是我的
Look what we almost took!
差點偷了這個
Excuse me,Mrs. Burkart?
柏卡特太太？
Well,we're all cleaned up.
廚房都收拾好了
Good. Thank you.
很好，謝謝你
And,well,there's this small matter of the....
還有一件小事…
-Dear? -The matter of...
什麼事？ 就是…
...payment.
費用的事
Jack used to handle the finances.
錢都是傑克在管
-You get it? -No,but I made a widow cry.
拿到了嗎？ 沒有，但是把未亡人惹哭了
See you in hell.
我們會被打下十八層地獄
You know what we should all do?
你知道嗎？
Go see a musical.
我們應該去看歌舞劇
Sure.
好
You know which one?
你知道應該看哪一部？
The 1996 Tony Award winner.
1996年東尼獎得獎作品
I mean,that one's gotta be good.
那部戲一定贊
Do you know the name of that one?
你知道它的名字嗎？
I don't know. Grease?
不曉得，「火爆浪子」？
不是
Rent?
「吉屋出租」？
Yes! Rent!
對！「吉屋出租」
So when do you want to go?
好，什麼時候去？
What? I'm sorry. I can't,I'm busy.
什麼？ 我不行，我很忙
Man,it is so hard to shop for girls.
天哪，女孩子的禮物真難買
Yes,it is...
的確很難…
...at Office Max!
文具店？
What did you get her?
你買了什麼？
A pen.
一支筆
It's two gifts in one. It's a pen that's also a clock.
這是二合一，是筆，也是時鐘
-You can't give her that. -Why not?
你不能送這個 為什麼？
She's not 11!
她不是小孩子
And it's not the seventh night of Chanukah.
這也不是光明節結束前夕
What he means by that is, while this is a very nice gift...
他的意思是，這個禮物雖然好
...maybe it's not something a boyfriend gives.
卻不適合送給女朋友
Sure it is.
當然適合
She needs a pen for work.
她上班要用到筆
She's writing. She turns it over. "It's time for my date with Joey!"
寫到一半轉過來一看 哇，該去跟喬伊約會了
All right. What did you get for Angela Del Veccio's birthday?
好 你送安琪拉什麼生日禮物？
She didn't have one.
我們交往時沒碰上生日
For three years?
整整3年？
Look,it's too late, and I got an audition.
已經來不及了，我還要試鏡
I can't shop anymore.
我不能再找了
I will go out and try to find something for her.
我去幫你找，好嗎？
Thanks,man.
謝了
While you're at it, could you get her a card?
你能不能順便買張卡片？
Would you like me to write her a little poem as well?
要不要我順便寫一首小詩？
Or just get a card that has a poem already in it.
或是買張印了詩的卡片
Oh,so it's a card, but it's also a poem-holder.
那是一張卡片，也是一頁詩
-You have to get our money. -She couldn't stop crying.
你得把錢要到 但是她哭個不停
With those thick glasses, her tears look giant.
眼淚還被眼鏡放大了
I know,it's tough.
我知道很難
You know what the first thing I did after my mom's funeral was?
你知道我媽一下葬我做了什麼
-What? -Pay the caterer!
什麼？ 付錢給外燴廚師
I've had a lot of jobs.
我做過很多工作
And there are some people who always try to get out of paying.
有些人總是想賴帳
It's either "That massage wasn't long enough"...
不是「按摩時間不夠長」
...or "l don't know any of those songs"...
就是「我沒聽過這幾首歌」
...or "These sombreros aren't big enough. Bad little white girl!"
或「這些墨西哥草帽不夠大」 「壞心眼的白妞」
So you think she's faking?
你覺得她在裝？
There weren't any tears till you showed her the bill.
你拿出帳單前她根本沒哭
She sounded pretty upset to me.
她聽起來很難過
She seems fine now.
現在似乎沒事了
So you just left? Her place was really that bad?
所以你就走了？ 她家真的那麼髒？
You throw your jacket on a chair at the end of the day.
我們下班回家 會把外套扔到椅子上
Like that,only instead of a chair, it's a pile of garbage.
在她家是扔到一堆垃圾上
And instead of a jacket, it's a pile of garbage.
那也不是外套，而是一堆垃圾
And instead of the end of the day, it's the end of time...
那也不是下班回家 而是世界末日
...and garbage is all that has survived.
只有垃圾存留下來
-Here. -Wow. Thanks.
拿去 謝了
So what happened?
然後呢？
Nothing. I had to get out of there.
哪有然後，我逃之夭夭
Next time,you take her to your place.
下次你就帶她去你家
I tried that. She says it has a weird smell.
我試過了，她說我家有怪味
-What kind of smell? -I don't know. Soap?
什麼怪味？ 不曉得，香皂味？
-Listen,you like this girl,right? -Yeah.
聽著，你喜歡她對吧？ 對
-You want to see her again? -Yeah.
你想再跟她見面？ 對
So you're going to have to do it in the mess!
那你就得在垃圾裡跟她做
Yeah,okay. You're right.
好吧，你說得對
I mean,who cares about a little sloppiness?
稍微亂一點又怎樣？
-It's endearing,really. -All right!
其實蠻可愛的 很好
Now you go get that beautiful pig!
去撂倒那只美麗的豬吧
I just spent the entire afternoon looking for a present...
我花了一下午替凱西找一件
...for Kathy that would be better than the rabbit.
比這隻兔子好的禮物
Any luck?
有找到嗎？
Yeah,I found this great place called "lnvisible Things for Kathy."
有，我找到一家店 叫「送給凱西的隱形禮物」
Can you give me a hand with all this stuff?
你能不能幫我搬一這些禮物？
Just return the book, let Joey give her the clock pen...
你就把書退回去 讓喬伊送她那支時鐘筆
...and you get her something worse than that...
你送個更差的東西，例如…
...Iike a regular pen.
一支普通的筆
She's really going to love this,you know?
她會很喜歡這本書
The bottom line is, I want her to have it...
我希望她擁有這本書
...even if I don't get to be the one who gives it to her.
就算不是我送的也行
Honey,that's so sweet.
好感人喔
You don't think it's just pathetic?
你不覺得很可悲嗎？
Oh,"pathetic"!
是「可悲」！
I've been looking all over for you.
我要去見凱西了，我到處找你
-Where? -Our place. The hall.
在哪裡找？ 家裡啦，大廳啦
I got something for her.
我找到禮物了
It's a book.
是一本書
A book?
書？
Is it a book that's also a safe?
是書也是保險盒？
It's a book that's just a book.
它就是一本書
It's the Velveteen Rabbit. It was her favorite as a kid.
是她小時候最喜歡的書 「天鵝絨兔寶寶」的珍本
So just let me know if she likes it,okay?
讓我知道她喜不喜歡，好嗎？
You got it. Thanks for doing this. I owe you one.
沒問題 謝謝你，我欠你一次
There wasn't any change from that twenty,was there?
那20塊沒有找錢是吧？
No,it came out to an even twenty.
沒有，剛好20塊
Wow. That's almost as much as a new book.
哇，跟新書差不多貴
-You didn't get the money? -Maybe I can try at intermission?
還是沒要到，對吧？ 等她暫停再去好了
You know what? Let's just go.
我們就走吧
We're not leaving till we get paid!
不行，錢沒拿到不能走
I don't know who she thinks she is.
她以為她是誰啊
I talked to the florist. She didn't get paid either.
我問過，花店也沒拿到錢
Or the limo driver,or the priest,and he can get the dead guy damned for all eternity.
還有靈車司機和神父 但他可以咒那個死人不得超生
Well,I'm not going back out there.
我不要再去了
Fine. Enough is enough!
好，我受夠了
Hey,widow?
喂，未亡人
Widow?
死老公的
Excuse me? Excuse me!
打擾一下
Thanks. Clearly this is a very,very hard time for you.
謝了 你現在當然十分難過
But we provided a service, and we deserve to be paid...
但我們提供服務 就該領到費用
...because you ate that service.
因為你吃都吃了
We are not leaving here until we are paid every penny,because...
錢沒付清我們不會走
...we're part-time caterers and we have no place else to go.
因為我們是兼職的，不必趕場
All right. I'll get my bag.
好，我去拿皮包
Good.
很好
I'm going to leave some cards here.
我留幾張名片
Please think of us for your next event.
下次有需要請考慮我們
So you want to come inside?
你想進來嗎？
Yes.
想
Yes,I do.
我想
I'll be right back. Make yourself comfortable.
我馬上回來，你隨便坐
Guess who?
猜猜我是誰？
Department of Sanitation?
衛生稽查人員？
It's me.
是我
What?
怎麼了？
Oh,Cheryl!
喔！雪柔
天哪…
-It's my hamster! It's Mitzi! -Oh,my God!
那是我的倉鼠，是蜜琪 天哪
I'm so sorry. I must have freaked out.
對不起，我嚇到了
Thank God it's not Mitzi!
幸好不是蜜琪
It's just a rat.
只是一隻老鼠
I did it!
完成了
I finished it! I did it all by myself!
我填完了 我一個人把它填完了
And there's nobody to hug.
卻沒有人可抱
Move!
Hey,you guys!
你們！
I finished it all by myself! Hug me.
我一個人把字謎填完了，抱我
太棒了
-Congratulations. -Thank you.
恭喜 謝謝
How did it go?
外燴辦得怎樣？ 過癮死了
The widow wouldn't pay, so Phoebe yelled at her till she did.
那個寡婦不肯付錢 菲比就罵到她付錢為止
I'm a hard-ass.
沒錯，我是狠角色
And I'm a wuss. We should be partners.
而我是軟腳蝦 我們應該聯手
Hard-ass and wuss. We could fight crime.
是啊 狠角色和軟腳蝦打擊犯罪
Wait a minute,Phoebe.
等一下，菲比
We should be partners.
我們是該聯手
We should be catering partners.
我們應該合夥辦外燴
You're not working now, and we have a great time together.
你想嘛，你現在沒工作 我們又合作無間
I cook and you take care of the money.
好 我下廚，你管錢
It'll be like I have a wife in the 50s!
我就像娶了個很傳統的老婆
How did she like the gift?
怎樣？她喜歡嗎？
She loved it. She's showing the girls right now.
她愛死了 她拿去隔壁給女生們看
Yeah? That's great.
是嗎？太好了
I got to tell you...
老實說
...I feel bad taking credit for this,because...
佔了這個功勞我很過意不去
...am I going to get a lot of credit for this!
我可有得爽了
-Happy birthday. -Thank you.
生日快樂 謝謝
You know,Chandler got you a gift too.
錢德也有禮物要送你
No,he didn't.
他沒有
Yeah,he did. Look, it's right there on the counter.
他有，看，就在餐檯上
Happy birthday.
生日快樂…
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
You really didn't have to.
你何必破費
You think it's just a pen,but you turn it over and it's also a clock.
你以為這是一支筆 其實轉過來還有時鐘
No,this is great!
好棒的禮物
-Thank you,Chandler. -Oh,yeah.
謝謝你，錢德 不客氣
Want to go to bed?
要睡覺了嗎？
I'll be in,in a minute.
我馬上就來
Don't forget your coupon.
別忘了帶猛男體驗券
Good night.
晚安
Thank you for the gift.
謝謝你的禮物
I just knew that sometimes when you're writing...
我只是想有時你寫字時
...you don't always know the exact time.
不一定知道確切時間
No,I didn't mean the pen. Thank you for the book.
我不是說這支筆 謝謝你那本書
The book?
書？
The Velveteen Rabbit?
「天鵝絨兔寶寶」
I have a feeling you had something to do with it.
我覺得跟你有關
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
When Joey gave it to me he said:
喬伊送我的時候說
"This is because I know you like rabbits,and I know you like cheese."
「因為我知道你喜歡兔子」 「也喜歡起司」
Thanks. I love it.
謝謝，我好喜歡
I know how hard it must have been for you to find.
你一定花了很多功夫
In case you missed that, that sound was,"Oh,well."
如果你沒聽到 我的意思是「還好啦」
You must really like Joey to go to all that trouble.
你一定很喜歡喬伊 才會這麼費心
Oh,yeah. He's my
是啊，他是…
He's my best friend.
他是我最要好的朋友
-Well.... -Good night.
晚安
Hey,that coupon expires,you know.
那可是限時體驗券
You don't know me. I'm Monica Geller,Ross' sister.
你不認識我 我是摩妮卡蓋勒，羅斯的妹妹
You know,it's too bad that didn't work out.
你好，可惜我們合不來
Anyway,he told me about your apartment.
總之他提到你家的情況
Well,I couldn't sleep thinking about it.
我想得睡不著
So would it be okay if I cleaned it?
我可以幫你打掃嗎？
不行嗎？
I won't be able to sleep.
我會睡不著